In conclusion, we've explored the key elements that make Amazon's operating plan so effective.
The process, while heavy weight, was the minimum amount of work we had to do to maintain
a strong understanding of and operational control over our business.
By defining clear initiatives, setting smart goals, resolving dependencies early, and
ensuring proper resource allocation, we greatly increased our chances of consistently achieving
our goals year after year.
This proactive approach allowed us to avoid costly surprises down the road and help
teams stay focused on what mattered most.
Through rigorous reviews and continuous feedback, we remained nimble and ensured
we stayed on track, even in the face of new data and shifting priorities.
As you implement these processes in your organization, it's important to remember
that while you can manage and control your inputs, you cannot directly control your
outputs.
If you accept this statement is true, about 70 or 80 percent of your energy, time,
and metrics will focus on customer-facing controllable inputs.
This ratio is much higher than we've seen at other companies, but it's also
a key reason for Amazon's consistent results delivery.
Finally, to successfully adopt this operating cadence, be sure to leverage the templates
and example documents we've provided.
These resources will guide you through the steps of setting up your own process.
Keep in mind that this is a significant process change, and if you decide to implement
it, you'll need at least six months before the start of your fiscal year to properly
prepare and adjust your organization to the new cadence.
We hope you've enjoyed this course on Amazon's operating cadence.
Thanks for joining us.